<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome :: Novian Andrian</title><link>https://andnovian.github.io/index.html</link><description>Thanks for visiting — I’m Novian 👋
I work as a Technical Lead Support Engineer, specializing in Microsoft Defender XDR. Most of my day is spent untangling complex Defender behaviors and helping others understand how to make the product work effectively in real-world environments.
Along the way, I’ve gained a deep understanding of how security products operate — and that hands-on experience has fueled my interest in cybersecurity.
This site is my portfolio — a place to:</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://andnovian.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://andnovian.github.io/about/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andnovian.github.io/about/index.html</guid><description>I didn’t plan to work in cybersecurity — I fell into it.
What began as a tech support job helping customers troubleshoot Microsoft Defender turned into an obsession. Within a year, I was the go-to person for deep-dive Defender issues. And now, I am Technical Lead supporting our team’s ramp up and escalations related to the Microsoft’s XDR stack.
My toolkit? Defender for Endpoint, Identity, Cloud Apps, Azure Sentinel — and a lot of KQL. I’ve supported customers across Windows, Linux, and macOS environments, bridging operations with Intune, GPO, and SCCM. When Defender tools didn’t behave as expected, I dug into the why — helping teams trace the root cause and build solutions that actually worked in the real world.</description></item><item><title>Credentials</title><link>https://andnovian.github.io/credentials/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andnovian.github.io/credentials/index.html</guid><description>Professional Certifications Microsoft Certified: Security Operations Analyst Associate (SC-200) Deep knowledge of Microsoft Defender XDR stack: MDE, MDI, MCAS/MDCA, MDC and Sentinel Skills: Incident response, threat hunting, KQL, Defender XDR Hands on Experience:
KQL queries for threat detection, hunting, and configuration auditing Setting up Microsoft Sentinel, and Defender XDR deployment Automated response workflows using Logic Apps, Powershell and Python with API integrations This certification reflects not just what I studied, but the skills I applied daily while helping customers improve their security operations.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://andnovian.github.io/contact/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andnovian.github.io/contact/index.html</guid><description>You can reach me on:
Email: Click to Copy EmailSocial: LinkedIn Reddit</description></item><item><title>My Blog Sharing</title><link>https://andnovian.github.io/blog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andnovian.github.io/blog/index.html</guid><description>Welcome to my blog. I will be updating regularly and will keep it updated. MS DefenderSentinel Playbook: Device Isolation Using MDE API #2Sentinel Playbook: Device Isolation Using MDE API #1Live Response to Remotely Collect Defender LogsTracking Defender Policy Deployment with Logs</description></item></channel></rss>